<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<document xmlns="http://di.tamu.edu/DRI/1.0/" xmlns:i18n="http://apache.org/cocoon/i18n/2.1" version="1.1">
    <body>
        <div id="file.news.div.news" n="news" rend="primary">
            <head>DSpace @ SEAFDEC/AQD</head>

            <p>
                Southeast Asian Fisheries Development Center, Aquaculture Department Institutional Repository (SAIR) is
                the official digital repository of scholarly and research information of the department. This is to
                enable the effective dissemination of AQD researchers' in-house and external publications for free and
                online. The repository uses DSpace, an open source software, developed at Massachusetts Institute of
                Technology (MIT) Libraries. It is an Open Archives Initiative (OAI)-compliant.
            </p>

            <p>
                Initially, the repository shall contain preprints, full-texts or abstracts of journal articles, books
                and conference proceedings written by SEAFDEC/AQD scientists and researchers. The aim is to promote
                these publications especially those published in international peer-reviewed journals and generate
                higher citation through increased visibility.
            </p>

            <p>
                It will also provide free access to all in-house publications of SEAFDEC/AQD. Full-text digitized copies
                of fishfarmer-friendly materials like books, handbooks, policy guidebooks, conference proceedings,
                extension manuals, institutional reports, annual reports (AQD Highlights), and newsletters (SEAFDEC
                Asian Aquaculture, Aqua Farm News, AquaDept News and AQD Matters) can be retrieved and downloaded.
            </p>

            <p>
                In the future, SAIR will expand its collection to include images, presentations, audios, and videos
                among others.
            </p>

            <p>
                The objectives of the repository are to: (1) to provide reliable means for SEAFDEC/AQD researchers to
                store, preserve and share their research outputs and (2) to provide easy access and increase the
                visibility of SEAFDEC/AQD scientific publications
            </p>

            <p>
                SAIR also aims to encourage SEAFDEC/AQD researchers for self-archiving and submitting pre-prints from
                which metadata will be screened and approved by the library staff.
            </p>

        </div>
    </body>
    <options/>
    <meta>
        <userMeta/>
        <pageMeta/>
        <repositoryMeta/>
    </meta>
</document>
